<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reasons to Use R on ADL publicsectR</title>
    <link>/tags/reasons-to-use-r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reasons to Use R on ADL publicsectR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>Kristen Osborne</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/reasons-to-use-r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reasons to use R in the public sector number 2: Efficiency</title>
      <link>/2019/12/01/2019-12-01-reasons-to-use-r-in-the-public-sector-number-2-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/01/2019-12-01-reasons-to-use-r-in-the-public-sector-number-2-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Background In the previous post on this blog, we introduced the idea of taking data that public servants routinely use and turning it into a figure that can be easily updated each time new data is added.
However, there was a step missing in that explanation: getting the data in a suitable shape.
But this is a really important function of a government data scientist (or any data scientist) because data is stored and shared in all sorts of shapes and sizes but to analyse it in R, we really need it in the shape that R needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reasons to use R in the public sector number 1: Replicability</title>
      <link>/2019/08/18/2019-08-18-reasons-to-use-r-in-the-public-sector-number-1-replicability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/18/2019-08-18-reasons-to-use-r-in-the-public-sector-number-1-replicability/</guid>
      <description>Start here  As public sector workers who do stuff with data we frequently find our bosses saying “Hey, could you make a plot of these data”. We say, “Sure!” and then we typically:
Open the data in Excel Cut out irrelevant bits and move stuff around so that it makes sense Plot it  This works pretty well and we’ve all gotten pretty good at it. But there are some problems beneath the surface that make our lives less fun and makes our work less useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>